Guide to the Jennette Howell Deal diaries,1892-1941.
Deal, Jennette Howell diaries
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Jennette Howell Deal diaries, 1892-1941.
3881
Jennette Howell, Deal 1876-1941.
40 v., 20 reels of microfilm.
Diaries; also available on microfilm (10 reels negative, 10 reels positive, 7150 microfilm exposures total).
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Forty volumes of diaries of Jennette H. Deal concerning her activities as a teacher and a farm wife, her participation in the Baptist church and other religious organizations, and the activities of family members. Many diaries also contain records of income and expenditures and lists of books read during the year.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Jennette H. Deal was born in Lima, New York on January 21, 1876 and grew up in Richmond, Ontario County, New York. In 1892 she completed teacher training school and began teaching in a one-room schoolhouse. In 1910 or 1911 she married Louis Prior, and they lived on a farm in Dundee, Yates County, New York. She died there on August 7, 1941.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Forty volumes of diaries of Jennette H. Deal concerning her activities as a teacher and a farm wife, her participation in the Baptist church and other religious organizations, and the activities of family members. Many diaries also contain records of income and expenditures and lists of books read during the year.
Note: Missing years of diaries: 1893, 1894, 1897, 1899, 1900, 1901, 1903, 1917, 1930.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Deal, Jennette Howell,1876-1941.; Prior, Louis.
Subjects:
Agriculture--New York (State)--Dundee.; Religion--New York (State)--Dundee.; Rural schools--New York (State)--Ontario County.; Teachers--New York (State)--Ontario County.; Farmers' spouses--New York (State)--Dundee.; Family--New York (State)--Dundee.; Women teachers.
Places:
Richmond (N.Y.); Ontario County (N.Y.); Dundee (N.Y.); Yates County (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- 1892, 80 pages (Reel 1)
- 1895, 201 pages (Reel 1)
- 1896, 206 pages (Reel 1)
- 1898, 105 pages (Reel 1)
- 1902, 199 pages (Reel 1)
- 1904, 198 pages (Reel 1)
- 1905, 200 pages (Reel 2)
- 1906, 73 pages (Reel 2)
- 1907, 199 pages (Reel 2)
- 1908, 198 pages (Reel 2)
- 1909, 199 pages (Reel 3)
- 1910, 192 pages (Reel 3)
- 1911, 200 pages (Reel 3)
- 1912, 188 pages (Reel 3)
- 1913, 186 pages (Reel 4)
- 1914, 187 pages (Reel 4)
- 1915, 186 pages (Reel 4)
- 1916, 185 pages (Reel 5)
- 1918, 185 pages (Reel 5)
- 1919, 185 pages (Reel 5)
- 1920, 189 pages (Reel 5)
- 1921, 185 pages (Reel 6)
- 1922, 183 pages (Reel 6)
- 1923, 93 pages (Reel 6)
- 1924, 95 pages (Reel 6)
- 1925, 94 pages (Reel 6)
- 1926, 184 pages (Reel 7)
- 1927, 185 pages (Reel 7)
- 1928, 187 pages (Reel 7)
- 1929, 188 pages (Reel 7)
- 1931, 184 pages (Reel 8)
- 1932, 185 pages (Reel 8)
- 1933, 188 pages (Reel 8)
- 1934, 185 pages (Reel 8)
- 1935, 190 pages (Reel 9)
- 1936, 192 pages (Reel 9)
- 1937, 184 pages (Reel 9)
- 1938, 190 pages (Reel 9)
- 1939, 191 pages (Reel 10)
- 1940, 187 pages (Reel 10)
- 1941, 108 pages (Reel 10)